Diego González Liarte

Software Developer

Location Spain, Lleida
Email diegogliarte@gmail.com
Phone +34 635 30 09 22
LinkedIn diegogliarte
GitHub diegogliarte

About me

With **2 years** in software development, I've worked as a **Backend** and **Full-Stack** Developer and ventured into **CLI** applications, **mobile** apps, **video games**, and **AR** in personal projects. My experience in small teams has also expanded my expertise into **DevOps**, adapting to varied roles beyond my official title

Experience

Sep 2023- Present

Software Developer, SEMIC

- Refactored and integrated a standalone Python script into an established Django application, enhancing functionality and improving system cohesion
- Automated testing and deployments using CI/CD pipelines with GitLab Runners
- Built Python servers using FastAPI to ease communication between different internal projects

Oct 2021 - March 2023,

Software Developer, Perspectiv

- Designed, implemented and deployed new modules for a pipeline of an existing application that connected to multiple RTSP cameras and used **machine learning** and **computer vision** to detect infractions committed by factory workers, with the usage of **Python**, **OpenCV** and **AWS**
- Created multiple **microservices** from an existing monolith using **Python**, **Redis**, **FastAPI** and **Docker**
- Automated deployments using CI/CD pipelines with GitHub Actions
- Undertook the role of a **QA** by creating unit and integration tests for a whole project consisting in +20k lines using **pytest**, as well as adding **documentation** and **monitoring** of various metrics

Education and Certifications

2019 - 2024

Double Bachelor's degree: **Computer Engineering and Business Administration and Management**, *Universitat de Lleida*

AI-102, AI-900, SC-900, DP-900 issued by *Microsoft*Google IT Automation Professional Certificate, issued by *Coursera*Google IT Support Professional Certificate, issued by *Coursera*Google Data Analytics, issued by *Coursera*First Certificate (B2), issued by *Cambridge*

Skills

Python, JavaScript, bash, Java, Kotlin, SQL, C/C++ HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Express, React, Node OpenCV, numpy, Flask, FastAPI, Django AWS, Unix, Docker, Git, GitHub, GitLab